(I never expected) all of you to be here present for the puja.
我從未期望你們全都能出席這個崇拜
I don't know how you all have managed to come.
我不知道你們是怎樣設法來到的
Otherwise, it's a very important day today for all of us
不管如何對我們所有人來說 今天是一個非常重要的日子
because you know
因為你們都知道基督是怎樣死的
Wonderful the way He said
祂卻以很非凡的方式
about you people.
談論你們大家
He asked for forgiveness from God.
祂請求神寬恕所有人
What we have to learn from His life is
我們要從祂的生命中學習的是
the way He knew how to forgive all of us.
祂懂得怎樣去寬恕 寬恕所有人
We have to also forgive people.
我們要寬恕人們
That seems to be very difficult for people to forgive.
對於人們來說去寬恕似乎是非常困難的
And if they are angry, they are angry,
而如果你是憤怒的 那麼你不能寬恕
Sahaja yogis must forgive, it's very important
作為霎哈嘉瑜伽士你必須去寬恕 那是非常重要的
because that is the power you have got from Christ: to forgive.
因為那正是你從基督處獲得的力量
Human beings make mistakes; that is a part of their life.
人類會犯錯 那是他們生命的一部分
But at the same time, as sahaja yogis you must remember that you have to forgive.
但同時作為霎哈嘉瑜伽士 你一定要明白你要去寬恕
That is much more important than getting angry.
這是比變得憤怒重要的多的
So to forgive people for doing something wrong according to you
所以去寬恕那些做了某些錯事的人
or according to God, you have to forgive.
對你或對神 你要去寬恕
And you will be surprised that the forgiveness
並且你會驚奇的發現寬恕
is such a great, satisfying quality.
是那樣偉大而美好的品格
If you can forgive people,
如果你可以寬恕
you will become extremely pure
你們將變得非常的純潔
because the dirt or the anger that is within us goes out.
因為你原本的污點和憤怒都消失了
So to forgive is the biggest blessings human beings have.
所以寬恕是人類所擁有的最大的祝福
Even Christ said the same thing
甚至基督也說著同樣的
that, "Forgive them because they don't know what they are doing."
我寬恕他們 因為他們不知道他們正在做什麼
So if Christ had to say, so what about you?
那麼如果基督曾這樣說 何況你們呢
We are ordinary human beings and if we have done mistakes,
我們都是普通人 如果我們犯了錯
people can get angry and upset with you.
人們可以生氣並使你不安
But the best thing for you is to forgive.
但對你們 最好的事情卻是去寬恕
Forgive for doing something that should not have been done.
寬恕那些做了不應該做的事情的人
This was the biggest quality of Christ: that He knew how to forgive.
這就是基督最偉大的品格 祂懂得怎樣去寬恕
And He forgave people who had made horrible mistakes.
祂寬恕曾經犯下可怕的過錯的人們
Still He forgave them because He loved them.
祂寬恕他們 因為祂愛他們
And that is what you should also forgive.
這就是為什麼你也要寬恕
Today is a special day for that - special day for forgiveness.
今天是一個特別的日子 一個寬恕的日子
And that is why I said, whatever you may think,
這就是為什麼我說不管你怎樣想
it's very late, but we'll have a meeting because I didn't want to miss the time.
時間很晚了 我們能彙聚一堂是非常好的 因為我不想錯過這個時機
Forgiveness comes by people who are very generous, who are good-hearted.
寬恕來自于寬厚的人 他們心地善良
You, everybody makes mistakes and so we can also make mistakes.
你知道 每個人都犯錯 我們也會犯錯
But that means we have a right to forgive
但這意味著我們擁有寬恕的權利
and we have a heart to forgive.
一顆寬恕的心
If you don't have, then we are not sahaja yogis.
如果你沒有 你就不是一個霎哈嘉瑜伽士
We must learn to forgive and forgive without any remarks behind it.
你必須學習寬恕 毫無保留地寬恕
Today is a very special day because that's what Christ did.
今天是一個非常特殊的日子 因為基督正是那樣做的
He was one of the most powerful deities or gods as we may say, most powerful.
可以這樣說 祂是最有力量的神祈 或天神之一 最具能量的
He could do anything; He could punish them, all of them, for misbehaving.
祂可以做任何事情 祂可以懲罰他們 他們所有人 為那錯誤行徑
But what did He say? He said, "I forgive"
但祂說過什麼 祂說 我寬恕
and He asked God also to forgive.
並且祂請求上帝也寬恕
So whatever may be your powers,
所以不管你擁有怎樣的力量
whatever you might have achieved in your life,
你的生活中成就了什麼
whatever position you might be occupying,
擁有怎樣的地位
but you must learn the way to forgive.
但你必須學習寬恕
Otherwise you are nowhere near Christ.
否則你不能接近基督
You must learn to forgive; that's a very great quality
你必須去寬恕 那是一種如此偉大的品格
if you can forgive, all the time forgive.
如果你能寬恕 始終寬恕
And that's why today I wanted to meet you all, so I did.
這就是今天我想要見到你們大家的原因
I wanted to meet you all and tell you
我希望見到你們並告訴你們
that today is a day to forgive.
今天是去寬恕的日子
That doesn't mean you sit down and think, oh, how many people you have to forgive.
這並不是說讓你坐下來 並思考有多少人你要去寬恕
That would be absurd.
那是荒謬的
But something that haunts your mind
但有些事情縈繞在你腦中
and you think you all been troubled and you have been put to trouble.
你感到苦惱 陷入混亂中
Then just think that you don't know how many powers you have
有意思的是你不明白你擁有多少力量
and you can't even forgive. When you have got all these powers;
你甚至不能寬恕 你擁有所有的力量
the greatest power you have got is to forgive.
而最大的力量是去寬恕
And today is the day for forgiving,
今天是寬恕的日子
forgiving people whom you think they have done wrong to you,
寬恕那些你認為對你做下錯事的人
or they have been unkind to you. Please try to remember
或對你不很友愛的人
Just forgive them. Then you have punished them.
只是寬恕 那麼你也因此得到寬恕
If you forgive them from your heart, then you have punished them.
如果你發自內心寬恕他們 你就已經懲罰了他們
You have given them back, whatever they wanted, they deserved.
你已經給回了他們希望的或應得的
So this is not a very difficult thing, to forgive,
所以 去寬恕這不是一件非常難的事情
but people think it's very difficult to forgive
但人們覺得寬恕是非常困難的
because they have certain great understandings about themselves.
因為他們覺得自己了不起
And then they think how can they forgive?
他們想 他們怎能去寬恕
I don't know what things upset you, anything can upset you.
我不知道什麼使你不安 任何事情都能使你不安
After all, you are all realized souls, you have got your second birth
畢竟 你們都是已獲自覺的靈 你已經獲得重生
and you are special people. So you should have a special quality.
是特別的人類 所以你應該具有不一般的品格
And the special quality is to forgive, to forgive.
去寬恕的特別品格 去寬恕
Not to go on remembering on what things you should be angry and you should be upset.
不要繼續記得你為什麼憤怒 為什麼不安
But just to remember what things you have to forgive. Just forgive.
只需記得有什麼要去寬恕 只是寬恕
For what?
為了什麼呢
Is a practical thing, most practical.
它是一個實際的事情 最實在的
Supposing somebody slaps me, alright.
設想某人用掌摑我 好吧
If somebody slaps me, what should I do?
如果有人用掌摑我 我應如何
I should slap him back? No.
我摑回他 不是
Then why should I ask him, "Why did you slap me?" No.
或我應問他 你為什麼打我 不是
Then I should think he must be stupid fool to do like that?
或我應想他一定是個愚蠢的傢伙才這樣做
Even that won't help. On the contrary, if you can just forgive,
這沒有用 相反 你可以只是寬恕
forgive that person who has done something wrong...
寬恕那個犯錯的人
For you it is important that you must forgive because has no effect.
對你來說你寬恕是重要的 因為其它的都沒有用
Once you forgive, it will have more effect on you, your goodness, your righteousness.
當你懂得寬恕 這對你的善行 你的美德都有更好的影響
But I think human beings find it difficult to forgive normally. Normally.
但我想人類發現去寬恕是困難的 通常如此 通常如此
But you are all realized souls; you are not only human beings.
但你們是已獲自覺的靈 你們不僅是人類
That's why I'm requesting you that remember you have a power to forgive.
這也是為什麼我正要求你記住 你擁有去寬恕的力量
To forgive everyone who hurts you,
寬恕每一個人 傷害你的人
who tortures you, who troubles you. How far can he go?
折磨你的人 麻煩你的人 你們能走多遠
Just think of forgiving him and you'll be amazed, he will change.
只是想著寬恕他 你將感到驚奇 他會改變
He will change and you will also enjoy yourself.
他將改變而你也將享受自己
It's a difficult thing for people to understand, but just try.
理解這些對人們是困難的 但請只是試試
Just try what I'm saying. If somebody does any harm to you,
只是嘗試我正在說的 如果某人傷害了你
just forgive that person and see the reaction,
只是寬恕那個人 並看看反應
reaction in that person and in yourself. What happens?
在那人和在你自己身上的反應 看會發生什麼
But if you want to carry the burden of his anger or of stupidity, whatever it is,
但如果你想要在憤怒 愚蠢或什麼的重負之中
then you are unnecessarily loaded with useless things.
你將毫無必要的令自己裝載著無用的東西
We should not waste our energy on deciding
我們不應浪費我們的精力來決定什麼是錯的
what's wrong, what did he do and what you should do to him, that we should not.
他做了什麼 你應對他做什麼 我們不應那樣
Just leave him alone and you just forgive. Say that, "I forgive."
只需別管他 並且你寬恕 說 我寬恕
Look at Christ. Such a powerful person; such a powerful god!
看看基督 如此有力量的人 如此有力量的神
And when He was crucified,
當祂被釘死十字架上
how He asked for forgiveness for them.
祂怎樣請求寬恕他們
Why did He do it? Because that has power.
為什麼祂這樣做 因為那就是力量
Saying, "Pa, forgive", it's very powerful.
說 我寬恕 是非常有力量的
You don't lose your power, but on the contrary,
你不要失去這力量 而是相反
you go higher in your power.
你在這力量上走的更高
You go higher in your personality.
在你的人格上走的更高
Just forgive. As simple as that.
只是寬恕 就這麼簡單
To say that, "I forgive," just like that.
說 我寬恕 就象這樣
That's how I do because people have their own whims
那正是我怎樣做 因為人們有他們自己的方式
and they do whatever they like, but I don't get angry on that point.
他們做他們喜歡的 但我不為那感到生氣
And I'm not upset on that point, neither I am concerned.
我既不對那感到不安 我也不關心
I just say, "I forgive," that's all.
我只是說 我寬恕 這是全部
And you'll be amazed, within myself, it so helps so much, really very helpful.
你會驚奇的發現 我自己內在 它幫助很大 真的非常有幫助
So this is a very big quality for which today is a special day.
對今天這個特殊的日子 這是一個非常好的品格
On the cross Christ said that, "Oh God, forgive them because they don't know
在十字架上 基督說 我希望上帝寬恕他們 因為他們不知道
what they are doing." On the cross where He was dying He said this,
他們正在做什麼 在十字架上 祂快要死了 祂這樣說
and what we have to learn is to forgive,
我們要學會去寬恕
for our sake, not for others. This helps us. If we forgive,
為了我們自己的緣故 不是為了其它人 這會幫助我們 如果我們寬恕
this will help us very much within ourselves.
這在我們自己內裡幫助非常大
This is the message for today and permanently. Permanently.
這是今天的啟示 也是永遠的 恒久不變的
Always, if you are angry with anyone, just say, "I forgive."
如果你對任何人感到生氣 只要說 我寬恕
If you find somebody hurting you or troubling you or torturing you,
如果你發現某人麻煩你 傷害你或折磨你
how you will overcome it? Just forgive, just forgive. This is the only way.
不管他們犯什麼錯 只是寬恕 只是寬恕 這是唯一的方法
Today that's why is very important day for us and I'm so very happy
今天對我們是非常重要的日子
Thank you.
謝謝你們